A Finding Aid to the Sidney C. Woodward Papers, 1823-1963, bulk 1915-1932, in the Archives of American Art AAA.woodsidn
Archives of American Art
Sidney C. Woodward papers
bulk 1915-1932
1823-1963
AAA.woodsidn
Archives of American Art
3.5 Linear feet
The papers of art critic, editor, and gallery director Sidney Woodward date from 1823 to 1963, bulk 1915-1932, and measure 3.5 linear feet. The majority of the collection consists of personal and professional correspondence and collected letters that pertain to Woodward's relationships with various artists, galleries, and arts organizations. Also included in this collection are two biographical documents; lecture notes and collected writings; printed material including books relating to the topic of art, exhibition catalogs, and newspaper clippings; a few personal photographs and reference photographs of paintings; and scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, art reproductions, and printed material from the Casson Galleries.
Woodward, Sidney C., 1890-1963
Biographical/Historical note
Sidney C. Woodward (1890-1963) was an art critic and editor in Boston, MA. Woodward collected letters and autographs from notable artists, as well as manuscripts relating to art and theater.
Woodward was born on December 11, 1890, in Malden, Massachusetts, son of Alice E. (Colesworthy) and Frank E. Woodward. He was one of eight children and a twin of Stanley, marine painter and illustrator. Woodward was an art critic and editor for the Boston Post, Boston Herald, and Christian Science Monitor; and gallery director of Casson Galleries, and Irving & Casson's art gallery in Boston, MA.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
A portion of the collection was purchased by the Archives of American Art from Sidney Woodward in 1963. Additional material was donated in 1975 by Mrs. Sidney C. Woodward.
Existence and Location of Copies note
Portions of this collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels D194-D196 and 439-440 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the collection as described in this finding aid may not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm due to reprocessing.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art critic, editor, and gallery director Sidney Woodward date from 1823 to 1963, bulk 1915-1932, and measure 3.5 linear feet. The majority of the collection consists of personal and professional correspondence and collected letters that pertain to Woodward's relationships with various artists, galleries, and arts organizations. Also included in this collection are two biographical documents; lecture notes and collected writings; printed material including books relating to the topic of art, exhibition catalogs, and newspaper clippings; a few personal photographs and reference photographs of paintings; and scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, art reproductions, and printed material from the Casson Galleries.
Artists that Woodward corresponded with and collected letters from include Ernest L. Blumenschein, Harrison Cady, Robert Henri, C. Lewis Hind, Rockwell Kent, John La Farge, Hermann Dudley Murphy, Violet Oakley, Water Pach, Elizabeth Robins Pennell, and Chauncey Foster Ryder, among many others. A significant number of letters in this collection were sent by his brother, marine painter Stanley, during his service in both World Wars.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 6 series.
Series 1: Correspondence and Collected Letters, 1823-1963 (2.2 linear feet; Box 1-3)
Series 2: Biographical Material, 1918 (1 folder; Box 3)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1880-1940 (0.1 linear feet; Box 3)
Series 4: Printed Material, circa 1880-1963 (0.4 linear feet; Box 3-4)
Series 5: Photographs, 1910s-1940s (4 folders; Box 4)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, circa 1920-1940 (0.7 linear feet; Box 5, BV 6-7)
Blumenschein, Ernest Leonard, 1874-1960; Cady, Harrison, 1877-1970; Casson Galleries.; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929; Hind, C. Lewis, (Charles Lewis), 1862-1927; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; La Farge, John, 1835-1910; Murphy, Hermann Dudley, 1867-1945; Oakley, Violet, 1874-1961; Pach, Walter, 1883-1958; Pennell, Elizabeth Robins, 1855-1936; Ryder, Chauncey F., 1868-1949; Woodward, Stanley Wingate, 1890-1970; Art critics--Massachusetts--Boston; Art galleries, Commercial--Massachusetts--Boston; Art--Collectors and collecting; Artists; Editors--Massachusetts--Boston; Gallery directors--Massachusetts--Boston; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Correspondence and Collected Letters, 1823-1963; Series 1; 2.2 Linear feet Box 1-3
  Scope and Contents note
  Found here is Sidney C. Woodward’s personal and professional correspondence and collected letters pertaining to Woodward’s relationships with various artists, galleries, and arts organizations.
  Included are many letters sent by Sidney’s twin brother, Stanley, while he was serving as a Corporal in Field Artillery during World War I and later as an Air Corps captain during World War II. Correspondence with Stanley primarily concerned his painting career, including some post card representations of his work.
  Artists that Woodward corresponded with and collected letters include Ernest L. Blumenschein, Harrison Cady, Robert Henri, C. Lewis Hind, Rockwell Kent, John La Farge, Hermann Dudley Murphy, Violet Oakley, Water Pach, Elizabeth Robins Pennell, and Chauncey Foster Ryder, among many others. Notable 19th century letters are written by Ivan Konstantinovich Aivazovsky, John White Alexander, Albert Bierstadt, Frederic Edwin Church, Winslow Homer, Francis Davis Millet, Thomas Moran, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, William Trost Richards, John Singer Sargent, and Thomas Sully.
  Also found here is correspondence with arts organizations, schools, and news organizations. This includes the Christian Science Publishing Society, the Erskine School, Frost & Reed, Knoedler & Co., and Robert C. Vose Galleries.
  Some photographs of artists are also included in folders of correspondence, including a portrait of Johannes Adam S. Oertel.
  See the Printed Material series for additional correspondence pasted into two books, Color and Method in Painting and The Etched Work of Franics Seymour Haden, which also include photographs and added annotations.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by person or organization name. Names with two or more letters are filed in their own folders, and the remainder of correspondence is filed in miscellaneous alphabetical files. Selected correspondents whose names do not appear in headings are indicated in a note following the folder heading.
  - A, Miscellaneous, circa 1877-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Adams, Wayman
    Adams, Woodhall
    Addison, A. H.
    Ahl, Henry Hammond
    Aivazovsky, Ivan Konstantinovich
    Albright, Susan F.
    Allen, Greer
    Allen, Louise (Mrs. Hobbs)
    Alma-Tadema, Sir Lawrence
    Anderson, Helge
    Anderson, Ruth (Mrs. Samuel Temple)
    Ansdell, Richard
    Arms, John Taylor
    Armstrong, Barbara
    Atkins, Albert Henry
  - Aiken, Charles Avery, 1915; 1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albert, Ernest, circa 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexander, John White, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Charles Curtis, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Marion Boyd, 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Oscar, 1925; 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anderson, Stanley, 1923-1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Applegate, Frank G., 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B, Miscellaneous, circa 1878-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Ball, Thomas Watson
    Bartlett, Paul Wayland
    Bates, Florence M.
    Battig, Chas. H
    Beach, W. M.
    Beal, Reynolds
    Beard, William Holbrook
    Beaux, Cecilia
    Beckwith, Carroll
    Bell-Smith, Frederic Marlett
    Benson, John P.
    Bevin, Alice Conklin
    Bissell, S.
    Blaney, Dwight
    Blashfield, Edwin Howland
    Blomfield, James
    Bogert, Mrs. George H.
    Bone, Muirhead
    Boughton, George Henry
    Bourne, Gertrude Beals
    Brackett, Walter M.
    Bradford, William
    Breckenridge, Hugh Henry
    Brierly, Sir Oswald W.
    Briggs, Clare A.
    Bristol, John Bunyan
    Brown, May Santori
    Browne, George Elmer
    Browne, Margaret Fitzhugh
    Brush, George de Forest
    Burdick, Doris
    Burgess, John Bagnold
    Burgess, Mrs. W. S.
    Burgess, R. L.
    Burroughs, Bryson
  - Bailey, Bertha, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bairnsfather, Arthur L., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ball, Alice Worthington, circa 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ball, Robert, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barton, Donald Blagge, 1933; 1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Benson, Frank Weston, 1923; 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bernstein, Theresa F., 1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bicknell, William Harry Warren, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bierstadt, Albert, undated; 1886 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bittinger, Charles, circa 1920-1927 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Blenner, Carle Joan, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Blumenschein, Ernest L., circa 1921-1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bodell, J. J., 1933; 1936 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bosley, Frederick Andrew, circa 1923-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Boston Herald, 1963; 1960-1961; 1931 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brown, Bolton Colt, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brown, Eric, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brown, Roy Henry, 1921; 1925-1926; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Browne, Belmore, circa 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Burrage, Mildred Giddings, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Burton, Arthur Gibbs, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - C, Miscellaneous, circa 1885-1959 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Cady, Harrison
    Calamatta, Luigi
    Campbell-Taylor, L.
    Carlsen, Dines
    Casson, Mr.
    Chalon, Alfred Edward
    Chase, Adelaide Cole
    Chase, Joseph Cummings
    Chase, Marion Monks
    Chase, Sidney Marsh
    Chelminski, Jan van
    Christian Science Monitor
    Christian Science Publishing Society
    Church, Frederic Edwin
    Church, Frederick Stuart
    Clark and Mills Electric Company
    Cobb, Bert
    Cole, Thomas
    Collver, Ethel Blanchard
    Conant, Marjorie (Mrs. Bush-Brown)
    Connick, Charles J.
    Cooper, Colin Campbell
    Cosimini, Roland Francis
    Costa, Giovanni
    Cotharin, Kate Leah
    Cox, Kenyon
    Cram, Allan Gilbert
    Crane, Bruce Robert
    Cross, Sally M.
    Crossett, Edward C.
    Cursiter, Stanley
  - Cabot, Julia Sewall, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Callis, Louis E., 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Carbee, Scott Clifton, 1915; 1920 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Carlson, John Fabian, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Carrington, FitzRoy, 1919; 1920; 1921 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Caser, Ettore, 1916-1931 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cassidy, Gerald, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Chadwick, Ernest A., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Chapman, Carlton Theodore, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Childs, Charles D., 1955; 1957; 1963; 1946 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Christie, Elizabeth, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Closson, William Baxter Palmer, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Coleman, Loring W., circa 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Costigan, John Edward, 1923; 1925 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Couse, Eanger Irving, 1928; 1924 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cowell, Joseph Goss, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Cratz, Benjamin, 1927; 1925 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Crawford, T. Hamilton, 1924-1929 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Curley, John Gee, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Curran, Charles Courtney, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - D, Miscellaneous, 1886-1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Davis, Henry William Banks
    Daws, Fred T.
    Dawson, Montague
    Day, Maurice
    De Grimm, Constantin
    De Groot, Adriaan Martin
    Delbos, C. Edmund
    Dicksee, Herbert
    Dielman, Frederick
    Dodd, Francis
    Doll & Richards, Inc.
    Dowling, G.
    Drury, John H.
    DuMond, Frank Vincent
  - Daugherty, James Henry, circa 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Davis, Charles Harold, 1919-1929 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - De Haven, Franklin, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Denison, Harold, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Detwiler, Frederick Knecht, 1923; 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - DeVoll, Frederick Usher, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Dixon, Maynard, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Douglass, Lucille Sinclair, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Drury, William H., circa 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Dugmore, A. Radcliffe, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Dunbar, Harold C., circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - E, Miscellaneous, circa 1842-1935 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Eastlake, Sir Charles Lock
    Eberle, Abastenia St. Leger
    Edwards, Samuel Arlent
    Ehrich, Walter L.
  - Emerson, Edith, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Enneking, Joseph Eliot, 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Ennis, George Pearse, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Eody, Henry Stephens, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Erskine School, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - F, Miscellaneous, circa 1858-1961 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Faed, John
    Faed, Thomas
    Fairbanks, Arthur
    Farquharson, Joseph
    Farrer, Henry
    Fay School
    Fechin, Nicolai Ivanovich
    Fenn, G. W.
    Ferriss, Hugh
    Flint, Sir William Russell
    Foster, Ben
    Foster, Myles Birket
    Freedley, George
    French, Daniel Chester
    Frick, Helen C.
    Frost & Reed Ltd.
    Fuchs, Emil
    Fuller, Henry Brown
  - Fisher, Anna S., 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Fiske, Gertrude, 1916-1932 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Folinsbee, John Fulton, 1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Foster, Ruth, undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - G, Miscellaneous, circa 1884-1931 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Gabriel, Gilbert R.
    Gaspard, Jules M.
    Geerman, Henry R.
    George, Vesper Lincoln
    Getchell, Edith Loring
    Gieberich, Oscar H.
    Gifford, Robert Gregory
    Gilbert, Henry F.
    Gledhill, William Edwin
    Gould, George L.
    Gregory, Edward John
    Griffin, Walter
  - Gallagher, Sears, 1919; 1921; 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Garber, Daniel, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Garrett, Edmund Henry, circa 1923 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Giddens, Philip Harris, circa 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Goodwin, Arthur Clifton, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Goodspeed's Book Shop, 1963; 1935; 1931 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Grafly, Charles Allan & Dorothy, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Grant, Frederic M., circa 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Gray, Joseph, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Griggs, Frederick Landseer Maur, 1932; 1930 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Gruppe, Charles Paul, undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - H, Miscellaneous, circa 1888-1933 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    Hale, Philip L.
    Hall, Frederick Garrison
    Hall, Oliver
    Hamilton, Hamilton
    Handforth, Thomas Scofield
    Hardick, Alice R.
    Hart, George Overbury (Pop)
    Hawthorne, Marion Campbell (Mrs. Charles Webster Hawthorne)
    Hedge, George S.
    Heil, Charles Emile
    Hennings, Ernest Martin
    Hill, George Snow
    Hinde, J. Donald
    Hitchcock, Mrs. Elizabeth
    Homer, Winslow
    Hooper, Alice Foster Perkins
    Hosmer, Harriet Goodhue
    Howe, William Henry
    Hoyton, E. Bouverie
    Huntington, Daniel P.
    Hurley, Edward Timothy
    Hutchinson, Charles
    Hyde, Helen
  - Hallowell, George Hawley, circa 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Hale, Lilian Westcott, 1920-1926 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Hammond, H. Knighton, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Hardie, Martin, 1928-1929; 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Harrison, Alexander, circa 1860s (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Hassam, Childe, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Hawkins, John W., 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Henri, Robert, 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Hibbard, Aldro Thompson, circa 1921-1933 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Higgins, Eugene, 1927; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Higgins, William Victor, 1923; 1925; 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Hind, C. Lewis, circa 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Hoffman, Harry Leslie, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Hoffman, Malvina, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Hopkinson, Charles Sidney, undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Hornby, Lester George, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Howell, Felicie Waldo, 1921-1922; 1931 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Hudson, Charles William, 1929; 1926 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Hudson, Eric, 1927; 1925 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Hughes, Christopher W., circa 1922-1928 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Ipsen, Ernest Ludwig, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Irvine, Wilson Henry, circa 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Ivins, William Mills, Jr., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - J, Miscellaneous, circa 1886-1933 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    James, Eldon R.
    James, William
    Joachim, Harold
    Johansen, John Christen
    Johnson, Horace Chauncey
    Jones, Francis Coates
    Jones, Hugh Bolton
    Jowett, Ellen
  - Jaques, Bertha Evelyn, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Jones, Haydon, circa 1922 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - K, Miscellaneous, circa 1915-1931 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    Kay, Gertrude Alice
    Kenyon, Henry Rodman
    Keyes, Grace B.
    Knoedler & Co.
    Kroll, Leon
    Kronberg, Louis
  - Kappel, Philip, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Kaula, William Jurian, 1927; 1925; 1933 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Keith, Elizabeth, 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1927; 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - King, Paul, circa 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Kinney, Troy, 1925; 1927; 1918; 1920 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Kirkpatrick, William Arber Brown, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Kirmse, Marguerite, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Kohn, Irma, circa 1922 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Komroff, Elinor Barnard, undated (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - L, Miscellaneous, circa 1855-1931 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    Ladd, Anna Coleman
    Lamb, F. Mortimer
    Landseer, Sir Edwin Henry
    Laurent, Robert
    Leighton, Sir Frederick
    Lewis, Martin
    Lincoln, Agnes Harrison
    Lippincott, William Henry
    Lucioni, Luigi
  - La Farge, John, 1909; 1901 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Lankes, Julius, J., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Lawless, Carl, 1923-1929 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Leigh, Howard, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Leigh, William Robinson, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Lever, Richard Hayley, 1921; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Levy, Bert, circa 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Lie, Jonas, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Little, Philip, 1920-1921; 1923 (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Lozowick, Louis, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - M, Miscellaneous, circa 1885-1962 (Box 1, Folder 137)
    MacCormick, Franklin D.
    MacKnight, Dodge
    Malden News
    Mansfield, Leslie
    Manship, Paul
    Martindale, Percy H.
    Marvin, F. H.
    Mayer, Constant
    Mayor, A. Hyatt
    McCartan, Edward
    Melchers, Gari
    Meltzer, Arthur
    Millet, Francis Davis
    Molarsky, Abraham
    Moran, Thomas
    Morley, Margaret W.
    Morse, Charles O.
    Munnings, Alfred
  - Macbeth, Robert Walker, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - MacDonald, James E. H., 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Manners, Victoria, circa 1925 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Margeson, G. T., 1920 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Meissonier, Jean Louis Ernest, 1881; 1891 (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Meyerowitz, William, circa 1919-1923 (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Minnigerode, C. Powell, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Moony, R. J. Enraght, circa 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Moorepark, Carton, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Morrow, Julie, undated (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Mulhaupt, Frederick John, circa 1926-1929 (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Murphy, Hermann Dudley, circa 1920-1933 (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Murphy, Nelly Littlehale, undated (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1955; 1925; 1923; 1823 (Box 1, Folder 151)
    Newton, A.
    Neyland, Harry
    Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson
    Northcote, William
  - Nelson, Wade B., 1920; 1918 (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Newell, George Glenn, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Nichols, Henry Hobart, circa 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - Nisbet, Robert Hogg, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Noble, John, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Nordell, Carl J., 1921 (Box 1, Folder 157)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1926; 1891 (Box 1, Folder 158)
    Ochtman, Leonard
    Orr, Louis
  - Oakley, Thornton, 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 159)
  - Oakley, Violet, 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 160)
  - Oertel, Johannes Adam Simon, circa 1880-1888 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Olson, J. Olaf, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Olinsky, Ivan G., 1925; 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - P, Miscellaneous, circa 1883-1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Paeff, Bashka
    Page, Walter Gilman
    Pairpoint, Nellie M.
    Parrish, Maxfield
    Parsons, Charles
    Patterson, Margaret Jordan
    Pearson, Ralph M.
    Pellegrini, Ernest G.
    Peterson, Jane
    Peterson, Kay
    Pettie, John
    Phillips, Clarence Coles
    Phillips, T.
    Picknell, William Lamb
    Pipe, H. Elizabeth
    Pleissner, Ogden M.
    Powers, Preston
    Pushman, Hovsept
  - Pach, Walter, 1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pape, Eric, 1912; 1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Paramino, John Francis, circa 1916 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Partridge, Roi, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Patterson, Charles Robert, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Pennell, Elizabeth Robins, 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Pennoyer, Albert Sheldon, circa 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pepper, Charles Hovey, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Perry, Lilla Cabot, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Peyton, Alfred Conway, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Piretti-Barth, E., 1920 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Plane, Georges, circa 1923 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Plummer, Ethel McClellan, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pooke, Marion Louise, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Poore, Henry Rankin, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Pullinger, Herbert, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - R, Miscellaneous, circa 1845-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Reich, Jacques
    Reinagle, Ramsay Richard
    Richards, William Trost
    Richardson, Francis Henry
    Richter, Herbert Davis
    Ritschel, William
    Robert C. Vose Galleries
    Roberts, David
    Robinson, Florence Vincent
    Roche, M. Paul
    Roerich, Nicolas Konstantin
    Rogers, John
    Rossiter, Henry P.
    Roth, Ernest David
    Ryerson, Margery Austen
  - Reddie, MacIvor, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Redfield, Edward Willis, 1921-1922; 1926 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Redmond, Margaret, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Reed, Ernest, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Richardson, Margaret Foster, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Roberts, Dean, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Roberts, Elizabeth Wentworth, circa 1920-1926 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rolshoven, Julius C., 1957; 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Rosenberg, Louis Conrad, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Rosseau, Percival Leonard, undated; 1922; 1920 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
  - Rotta, Antonio, circa 1890s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Rungius, Carl Clemens Moritz, 1922-1931 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Ruyl, Louis H., 1920; 1918; undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ryder, Chauncey Foster, 1921-1927 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Ryder, Chauncey Foster, circa 1914-1922 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - S, Miscellaneous, circa 1831-1933 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Saint-Gaudens, Augustus
    Sargent, John Singer
    Satterlee, Walter
    Seaton, Roger
    Schwarz, Frank
    Selden, Dixie
    Sharp, J. H.
    Shee, Sir Martin Archer
    Shelton, William Henry
    Shope, Henry Brengle
    Short, Sir Frank
    Skoog, Karl Frederick
    Skou, Sigurd
    Snyder, Edward J.
    Small, Philip L.
    Smith, Frank Vining
    Smith, Ismael
    Smith, J. Andre
    Smith, Sidney S.
    Sohier, Alice Ruggles
    Soldwedel, Frederic
    Soper,T. George
    Spiers, Harry
    Stanton, H. Beresford
    Sterner, Albert Edward
    Stevens, William Lester
    Stoddard, Frederick Lincoln
    Sully, Thomas
  - Saling, Paul E., 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sanborn, Earl E., circa 1922 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Sandzen, Sven Birger, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Sarka, Charles N., 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Schaefer, Frederic, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Schofield, Walter Elmer, 1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 45)